<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Kyohei Yazawa Site</title><link href="https://kyoheiyazawa.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://kyoheiyazawa.com/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://kyoheiyazawa.com/</id><updated>2019-07-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Ontology of Hamburgers</title><link href="https://kyoheiyazawa.com/blog/hamburgers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-07-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kyohei</name></author><id>tag:kyoheiyazawa.com,2019-07-19:/blog/hamburgers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I know of no food that is more essentially American than the hamburger. Determining who invented the hamburger is like trying to find the one cow that provided the ground beef for your hamburger patty. A herd of enterprising immigrants to America all claim to have made the very first …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I know of no food that is more essentially American than the hamburger. Determining who invented the hamburger is like trying to find the one cow that provided the ground beef for your hamburger patty. A herd of enterprising immigrants to America all claim to have made the very first hamburger in the late 1800s. And the rest is history. The hamburger has a simple basic form, which leaves plenty of room for customization to make it unique, gourmet, or just plain weird. It's a lowbrow food that transcends class boundaries and has taken over the world. Hamburgers are also quite unhealthy. Like its birthplace of America, the hamburger can be problematic, but in its best manifestations it is egalitarian and free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't really cook hamburgers because I find them to be too smoky to make in my small apartment, but I do eat a fair number of burgers that other people have made. I have a beef with many hamburgers, which is that the patty is too thick. This may be an unpopular opinion, but I think beef by itself doesn't really have an interesting taste and is sort of bland (I have never really liked steaks for this same reason). I appreciate the beef patty in a hamburger when it moderates but also gives heft to the other, stronger flavors in a hamburger, and I also appreciate the smoky crust formed by the so-called Maillard reaction. My cooking hero J. Kenji López-Alt has an informative &lt;a href="https://aht.seriouseats.com/2012/09/the-burger-lab-smashed-burgers-vs-smashing-burgers.html"&gt;blog post on the benefits of the burger-smashing technique in developing this crust on the patty.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently had a Five Guys burger for the first time. I requested a single patty burger but received a double patty all the same. In my opinion, this was a very unbalanced burger that contained far too much beef. To make matters worse, apparently &lt;a href="https://www.mashed.com/60752/make-perfect-five-guys-burger/"&gt;Five Guys does not add salt to their meat as a matter of policy.&lt;/a&gt; As a result, the burger had an aggressively bland and dry flavor, which made me sad (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kenjilopezalt/status/1145049158245470209"&gt;and I am joined by some prominent voices in disliking Five Guys!&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, one of the best places in the world to get a hamburger is Paris—the capital of anti-American snobbery. The city is full of small, casual burger joints serving quality burgers. Unfortunately, many of them close after lunch and don't reopen until around 7 p.m. When I found myself in Paris wanting a burger in the afternoon, I could only find one nearby place that was open out of perhaps a half-dozen. I remember the burger I had there was quite tasty, but today I searched for the place on Google Maps and I couldn't find it. Perhaps it went bankrupt due to being open in the afternoon. If you are ever in Paris, be sure to eat at a Parisian hamburger joint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Closer to home, I think that Shake Shack and Smashburger are solid places to grab a burger. There are undoubtedly other, more gourmet places that serve burgers, but burgers lose some of their appeal for me when they become serious sit-down affairs. I think that burgers are most true to their essence when they are quick, easy, and manageable, and I find that Shake Shack and Smashburger best fulfill this ideal. They both serve fairly small burgers, and I appreciate that I don't feel horribly weighed down by their burgers after eating them. I would say that Shake Shack burgers are more disciplined and balanced, while Smashburger is more wacky in their flavors and presentation. In Minnesota, both of these chains are only located in the suburbs for some reason. I would love to see Shake Shack and Smashburger expand to more urban locations in Minnesota. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MyBurger is a Twin Cities local burger chain with quite a few urban locations. I work right next to one so I go there relatively often. I am curious to know if they are affiliated in any way with MyPillow, another local business empire. Luckily, MyBurger does not print their CEO's likeness everywhere that they can, &lt;a href="https://www.bizjournals.com/twincities/news/2019/03/04/report-of-deranged-person-hugging-pillow-in-snow.html"&gt;unlike MyPillow&lt;/a&gt;. While MyBurger serves perfectly acceptable burgers, in my opinion they are a little too clean and Teutonic in character. The best hamburgers are messy and dripping with juices—and biting into them almost feels transgressive. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Ukrainian Travel Show Heads and Tails</title><link href="https://kyoheiyazawa.com/blog/ukrainian-travel-show-heads-and-tails.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-06-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kyohei</name></author><id>tag:kyoheiyazawa.com,2019-06-17:/blog/ukrainian-travel-show-heads-and-tails.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I was planning a trip to London and Paris last year, I didn't turn to Rick Steves or Lonely Planet for guidance. Instead, I took to YouTube to watch my favorite travel show, &lt;em&gt;Heads and Tails&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Heads and Tails&lt;/em&gt; (Орёл и Решка) is a Russian-language TV show produced by …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I was planning a trip to London and Paris last year, I didn't turn to Rick Steves or Lonely Planet for guidance. Instead, I took to YouTube to watch my favorite travel show, &lt;em&gt;Heads and Tails&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Heads and Tails&lt;/em&gt; (Орёл и Решка) is a Russian-language TV show produced by a Ukrainian company. I found this show while looking for fun ways to study Russian. Luckily for us Americans who can't watch this show on broadcast TV, the production company of &lt;em&gt;Heads and Tails&lt;/em&gt; posts full episodes of the show on YouTube. It's unclear to me how this show is profitable when it is available for free online, especially considering its expensive production format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="embed-container"&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Zkz7_GRMUy4" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each episode of &lt;em&gt;Heads and Tails&lt;/em&gt; is presented by two hosts, and begins at the airport. The London episode shows the two hosts who have just arrived at Heathrow Airport and are ready to start their weekend vacation in London. One of them is wearing a backpack, and the other is holding the &lt;em&gt;Heads and Tails&lt;/em&gt; golden credit card. One of the hosts greets their new destination with a "&lt;em&gt;Privet&lt;/em&gt;, London!" and flicks a £1 coin into the air. The coin toss decides which of the hosts gets the golden card for the weekend, while the other host is left with the backpack. The host with the golden credit card can spend an unlimited amount of money with the card, while the other host must backpack through the weekend, living off a single $100 bill. After much rejoicing from the bearer of the golden card and grumbling from the backpacker, the two hosts part ways. The backpacker gets gouged by the airport money changer to exchange their $100 for local currency, and then heads to the city on public transit, while the golden host gets picked up at the airport in an ostentacious sports car, ready to live like a millonaire for the weekend. At the end of each episode, the hosts prepare a bottle with $100 tucked inside and hide it in a secluded location, and show you directions on how to find the treasure.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a super fun format for a travel show, and I'm surprised something similar doesn't exist on English language TV. Having been the backpacker with the $100 bill myself, I am impressed with how accurately &lt;em&gt;Heads and Tails&lt;/em&gt; captures the unpredictable nature of budget travel within a slickly produced TV show, and while I'm sure various preparations are happening off camera, the show feels very real and authentic to me. In some locations, $100 is actually a substantial amount of money in relation to the average local wage, and the host can live quite comfortably for the weekend. In some expensive cities, living on $100 is a real challenge, but even in those situations the hosts always do a great job of showcasing fun free things to do in a city. On the other hand, the host with the golden card can show a side of a destination that most of us will never get to experience, which is fun in its own way. Around the megacities of the world, the golden card provides access to jaw dropping hotel rooms and deluxe gastronomic experiences involving very small portions of food. In less touristic destinations, the host with the golden card tends to splash out for experiences that seem more outrageous than luxurious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each season revolves around a particular theme. My favorite was Season 7's "Back in the USSR," in which my favorite &lt;em&gt;Heads and Tails&lt;/em&gt; hosts, Andrey Bednyakov and Nastya Korotkaya, visit fascinating locations around the former Soviet Union, from the dapper Baltic states, to places off the tourist radar in the Caucasus, Central Asia, and the Russian Far East, to sprawling Moscow, where they finish the season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many episodes leave me  wondering which host enjoyed themselves more—the backpacker or the golden card holder. Many doors are opened by money, but money might cause you to overlook some experiences too. Most of my travel experiences have been of the budget variety, and while this led to many fond memories, I also didn't have the option of traveling any other way, so I'm always curious to see what happens when a &lt;em&gt;Heads and Tails&lt;/em&gt; host splashes out for a luxurious travel experience. Your financial situation really colors your experience of a place, and this is true whether you live somewhere or are just passing through. &lt;em&gt;Heads and Tails&lt;/em&gt; is a strange examination of the hugeness of human life—at each place they travel to they find unique customs, languages, cuisines, and architecture, with the rich and poor going about their mostly separate lives.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Emacs Japanese Font Config</title><link href="https://kyoheiyazawa.com/blog/emacs-japanese-font-config.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-06-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kyohei</name></author><id>tag:kyoheiyazawa.com,2019-06-16:/blog/emacs-japanese-font-config.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm currently trying out using emacs as my main editor. I especially like that I can open up the eww web browser in a window, and research things on the web without leaving emacs. It is a big problem when I am coding, switch over to my browser to research …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm currently trying out using emacs as my main editor. I especially like that I can open up the eww web browser in a window, and research things on the web without leaving emacs. It is a big problem when I am coding, switch over to my browser to research a problem I have, and 30 minutes later find myself on Wikipedia reading about some random nematode found in Atlantic fish. eww is surprisingly functional for a text based web browser, but it is ugly and clunky enough to keep me focused on my work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I discovered that Japanese text renders horribly in emacs/eww. This is on Fedora Linux. When I opened a Japanese site in eww, it was a terrible mix of serif and sans-serif fonts, some of which were anti-aliased and some that were not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I struggled to find a simple solution to this when searching on the English language web. However, I immediately found a great solution on the Japanese web, on &lt;a href="http://asukiaaa.blogspot.com/2017/11/ubuntuemacs.html"&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I needed was this one-liner in my emacs config:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;(set-fontset-font t &amp;#39;japanese-jisx0208 &amp;quot;Noto Sans CJK JP&amp;quot;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Set the font name as desired. The addition of this line to my emacs config seems to be working great for my needs. I now have consistent font display on Japanese sites in eww. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Pokémon Detective Pikachu</title><link href="https://kyoheiyazawa.com/blog/pokemon-detective-pikachu.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-06-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kyohei</name></author><id>tag:kyoheiyazawa.com,2019-06-02:/blog/pokemon-detective-pikachu.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently saw &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Detective Pikachu&lt;/em&gt; in theaters. The discourse around the movie has generally been negative, so I went in with low expectations, but I surprised myself by having a great time! Justice Smith plays the charming main character Tim, a mild mannered insurance adjuster with a repressed love …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently saw &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Detective Pikachu&lt;/em&gt; in theaters. The discourse around the movie has generally been negative, so I went in with low expectations, but I surprised myself by having a great time! Justice Smith plays the charming main character Tim, a mild mannered insurance adjuster with a repressed love of Pokémon who goes on an adventure to find his dad. Through &lt;em&gt;Rashomon&lt;/em&gt;-like twists and turns, Tim must wade through conflicting accounts of a car crash that is tied to his dad's disappearance. This was an exciting storyline with a lot of heart, and it's nice that Tim searches for his dad given that the original Pokémon Game Boy games have you start your adventure by leaving your mom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ryan Reynolds as the voice of Pikachu is the more controversial aspect of this movie, although I think for most people the choice of Ryan Reynolds is less outrageous than the fact that Pikachu talks at all. The &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/broderick/status/930126330615730182"&gt;viral clip of Pikachu briefly speaking English&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Pokémon the Movie: I Choose You!&lt;/em&gt; is still a fresh trauma. Although I was laughing along with the rest of the internet when the &lt;em&gt;Detective Pikachu&lt;/em&gt; trailers first came out, after having seen the movie I think that Ryan Reynolds did a good job playing Pikachu in a goofy but sincere way. The other potentially weird thing about this movie is that it has CGI Pokémon that are seamlessly integrated into live action. It was initially shocking to see Pikachu covered in realistic yellow fur in the &lt;em&gt;Detective Pikachu&lt;/em&gt; trailer. There is something unsettling about encountering a beloved cartoon character in the flesh. (Artist &lt;a href="https://miguel_vasquez.artstation.com/"&gt;Miguel Vazquez&lt;/a&gt; has played with this idea by creating some terrifying realistic renditions of characters from &lt;em&gt;The Simpsons&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Hey Arnold&lt;/em&gt;, and other cartoons.) So the creators of &lt;em&gt;Detective Pikachu&lt;/em&gt; had to strike a fine balance of not making the Pokémon look &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; realistic, while also not making them look video gamey and fake. I think they mostly got it right, with a few exceptions (among them a scary looking Charizard with weirdly textured skin). The visuals throughout the movie are gorgeous. Ryme City, the setting of the movie, is futuristic and colorful as a Pokémon city should be, but it also feels like a place where real people live and work. It was believable and really cool to see Pokémon inhabiting a live action world just as if they were normal animals. Throughout the movie, Tim wears a leather jacket—but did the leather come from a dead cow or a Tauros? These and other "are Pokémon animals" questions sadly remain unanswered in &lt;em&gt;Detective Pikachu&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1996, &lt;em&gt;Pocket Monster Red&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Pocket Monster Green&lt;/em&gt; were released in Japan for the Nintendo Game Boy. In the following few years, Pokémon became a trading card game, then a TV show, then a worldwide cultural phenomenon. It occurs to me that I am part of a unique generation of people that entered childhood just as Pokémon was coming into existence. When I was growing up, Pokémon was described as a "craze," I think with the expectation that it would soon self-combust and fade away, just like a sugar rush. Today, 23 years later, Pokémon's earliest fans such as myself aren't so young anymore, but Pokémon is still new and exciting—not just confined to the 90s nostalgia bin. Pokémon has had incredible cultural staying power over the years, perhaps only exceeded by that of the &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; franchise. In recent years, Pokémon has birthed the versatile "Surprised Pikachu" meme, ruined smartphone batteries around the world with &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt;, and even served as the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o95KxKKrgkQ"&gt;poetic inspiration for a Republican Presidential candidate&lt;/a&gt;. On another note, I actually ended up seeing &lt;em&gt;Detective Pikachu&lt;/em&gt; a second time with a group spanning ages 8 to 28, and we all had a blast, which I think speaks to the incredible power of Pokémon to speak to kids, or the former kids within us. The movie made me want to dig out my old Game Boy and &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Blue&lt;/em&gt; cartridge, but I also can't wait to see what new Pokémon thing comes out next.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Stephen King: Maximum Overdrive</title><link href="https://kyoheiyazawa.com/blog/stephen-king-maximum-overdrive.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-04-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kyohei</name></author><id>tag:kyoheiyazawa.com,2019-04-01:/blog/stephen-king-maximum-overdrive.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have never actually read a Stephen King novel, though I have watched and enjoyed many movies based off of his stories such as &lt;em&gt;Carrie&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;It&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Gerald's Game&lt;/em&gt;. However, I recently finished his memoir &lt;em&gt;On Writing&lt;/em&gt;, which I highly recommend to anyone interested in writing as a craft. In …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have never actually read a Stephen King novel, though I have watched and enjoyed many movies based off of his stories such as &lt;em&gt;Carrie&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;It&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Gerald's Game&lt;/em&gt;. However, I recently finished his memoir &lt;em&gt;On Writing&lt;/em&gt;, which I highly recommend to anyone interested in writing as a craft. In the book, King briefly recounts his life and career and lets you peek under the hood of his hit factory. King is full of unpretentious and solid writing advice that is sure to benefit anyone who takes writing seriously.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But aside from the writing advice, this disarmingly honest passage from the book piqued my interest:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides, if you really did write a stinker—it happens; as the author of &lt;em&gt;Maximum Overdrive&lt;/em&gt; I'm qualified to say so...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this is some of that King magic in action—this passage had me dying to learn more about his worst work. In &lt;em&gt;Maximum Overdrive&lt;/em&gt;, Stephen King is more &lt;em&gt;auteur&lt;/em&gt; than author. &lt;em&gt;Maximum Overdrive&lt;/em&gt; is a movie based on the Stephen King short story "Trucks," and it is also the first and only movie directed by King. Stephen King makes a cameo appearance in the film as a man who becomes enraged when a rogue ATM display tells him that he is "an asshole," and he even appears in the movie's trailer, which you can watch below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="embed-container"&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ggWS4tTzs60" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite part of the trailer is when Stephen King points at the camera with crazed-looking eyes and says, "I'm going to scare the hell out of you!" This is a refreshing change from modern trailers that show too much and ruin the plot and the best jokes of a movie, so more directors should do this. According to Wikipedia and multiple YouTube commenters, King was in a cocaine-addled state for much of this movie's production, so that could explain his strange appearance in the trailer.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can tell from the trailer, &lt;em&gt;Maximum Overdrive&lt;/em&gt; has a fabulous soundtrack that is a mix of 80's synth sounds and the music of AC/DC, which was a brilliant directorial choice. AC/DC's obnoxious anthems are the ideal match for the atmosphere of this strange movie.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The setup of the movie is that humanity comes under attack when some sort of supernatural comet casts its dark influence upon Earth, causing all machines to become sentient and murderous. Our main characters seek refuge in a rural truck stop as 18-wheelers circle around them. Stepping outside means certain death accompanied by a weird alarm sound that plays whenever a truck kills someone.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can understand Stephen King referring to this movie as a "stinker," because it is undeniably bad. I did end up watching the whole movie, but I do have to agree with the assertion that "the trailer was scarier than the movie lol" by YouTube commenter BigKnGa. The acting is mediocre to bad all around, and the story is fairly boring at times due to a lack of action. The worst of these lulls is when the humans are forced to spend hours refueling an endless caravan of 18-wheelers queued up at the truck stop while "Hells Bells" by AC/DC plays in the background.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more fundamental problem with this movie is that trucks are simply not that scary on screen. Trucks are mundane looking, rather plain objects. Mechanical villains being unscary is a problem in other films as well, such as the 2004 &lt;em&gt;I, Robot&lt;/em&gt; starring Will Smith. We humans still react most viscerally to our animal fear of a threatening pair of eyes, and sharp, glistening teeth and claws. Though the trailer shows Stephen King standing in front of a truck with a horrifying devil face on the front (please, give whoever designed this prop an award!), I was disappointed to learn that the face is not the result of a supernatural transformation, but is simply a plastic display ornament placed on the truck by its owner before the start of the truck rebellion. After watching the trailer, I was expecting a dark Thomas the Tank Engine sort of thing where all of the trucks sprout horrible faces. Perhaps this was not possible due to budget or the production possibilities of the time. With advancements in CGI technology, I have great hopes for a remake of this film directed by a now sober Stephen King, starring trucks transformed by dark cosmic magic into horrifying giant beasts with jaws dripping with malice and motor oil that devour any human in their path. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>American Idiot: A Retrospective</title><link href="https://kyoheiyazawa.com/blog/american-idiot-a-retrospective.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kyohei</name></author><id>tag:kyoheiyazawa.com,2019-03-23:/blog/american-idiot-a-retrospective.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;American Idiot&lt;/em&gt; is one of the most popular albums by Green Day. Released in 2004, it delivered chart-smashing success for Green Day against the backdrop of the 2004 U.S. presidential election and its overarching theme — the Iraq War. Though the album is full of strong singles such as "Holiday …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;American Idiot&lt;/em&gt; is one of the most popular albums by Green Day. Released in 2004, it delivered chart-smashing success for Green Day against the backdrop of the 2004 U.S. presidential election and its overarching theme — the Iraq War. Though the album is full of strong singles such as "Holiday" and "Wake Me Up When September Ends," the entire album is tied together by a rock opera concept in the same vein as the Who's &lt;em&gt;Tommy&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;American Idiot&lt;/em&gt; tells the story of Jesus of Suburbia, a troubled, unremarkable teen from a generic American suburb.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;American Idiot&lt;/em&gt; was the hottest shit when it came out while I was in middle school. Everyone went nuts about it and the songs were all over the radio. The black Parental Advisory label on the CD cover prevented some kids from obtaining the CD but strengthened its anti-authoritarian message. We resented Tipper Gore's legacy while wishing her husband were the president instead of the Doonesbury asterisk who sat in the White House. The album is packed full of catchy songs, and I can still play all of the songs from the album on guitar — an easy accomplishment since the entire album is power chords over meat and potatoes sort of progressions. While a lot of good music was produced in this era, &lt;em&gt;American Idiot&lt;/em&gt; more than any other album of this time confronted head-on the alienation I and my peers felt at suburban monoculture and American chauvinism close to home, and the criminal acts of an isolated America abroad. I grew up in the environs of Boulder, a blue enclave within red Colorado. I imagine people who grew up elsewhere experienced this era quite differently. Thinking back on it now, I think that the Bush II era is when the fraying apart of American society really began in earnest. &lt;em&gt;American Idiot&lt;/em&gt; is for me (and I suspect many others of my generation) the definitive soundtrack to this important time period in our lives and American history.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are my top 3 tracks from &lt;em&gt;American Idiot&lt;/em&gt;, ranked.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. Give Me Novacaine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="embed-container"&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/r1-YMsOUE2I" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intro has a sweeter melody compared to the rest of the songs on the album and a slide guitar sound lends it a slightly loopy feel. The song's theme of sedation works well with the contrast in sound between this part and the aggressive electric guitar-backed verses, which are classic Green Day. Stabbing the V chord at the end of the chorus to build tension is stereotypical Green Day as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. Boulevard of Broken Dreams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="embed-container"&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Soa3gO7tL-c" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The incredibly iconic intro of "Boulevard of Broken Dreams" is probably my second favorite usage of guitar tremolo (my favorite is in the epic outro of the song "Black Sabbath" on the album &lt;em&gt;Black Sabbath&lt;/em&gt; by the band Black Sabbath). Note that Green Day repeat their trick of ending the chorus by hammering on the V chord in this song — why mess with a winning formula?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Jesus of Suburbia&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="embed-container"&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FNKPYhXmzoE" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Jesus of Suburbia" seems be the song where Green Day tried their hardest to realize their rock opera concept for &lt;em&gt;American Idiot&lt;/em&gt;. The song transitions seamlessly between five movements, each with a completely different sound and character. It is nine minutes long and not boring for a single second. Near the end of the last "Tales of Another Broken Home" movement there is a lovely "movement within a movement" that is one of my favorite parts of the song but always throws me off when I play this song on guitar. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>REVIEW: Bad Blood - John Carreyrou</title><link href="https://kyoheiyazawa.com/blog/theranos.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kyohei</name></author><id>tag:kyoheiyazawa.com,2019-03-12:/blog/theranos.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bad Blood is the story of the rise and fall of Theranos. Theranos was a medical startup that promised to make veinous blood draws obsolete by running a variety of blood tests via a prick of the finger. The company had ambitions to place a Theranos device in every home …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bad Blood is the story of the rise and fall of Theranos. Theranos was a medical startup that promised to make veinous blood draws obsolete by running a variety of blood tests via a prick of the finger. The company had ambitions to place a Theranos device in every home in America. People would be able to prick their finger and place a drop of blood in their Theranos device, and receive their blood test results right away, all within the confines of their living room.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Theranos never even came close to solving the engineering challenges required to make this dream a reality. This is a predictable conclusion in retrospect. Theranos's core idea of making blood testing devices use less blood is fairly obvious and must have occurred to the established multinational medical device manufacturers as well - why would the upstart Theranos succeed where they had failed?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theranos didn't let reality stand in the way of its march towards success. Theranos promised capabilities it did not have to enter partnerships with large chains such as Safeway and Walgreens to place Theranos testing centers in their retail locations. Engineers working at Theranos who were bullied into working late nights and weekends did make some progress, but the product they created was nothing more than a prototype, and often gave wildly inaccurate results for many blood tests. Rather than hit the brakes at this point as any responsible company would, Theranos decided to proceed with testing real patients' blood with cavalier disregard for their health and safety.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theranos's trajectory was tightly bound with the personality of its founder and CEO, Elizabeth Holmes. Bad Blood is as much about Holmes the person as it is about Theranos the company. Holmes dropped out of Stanford to start Theranos. She deftly leveraged family and Stanford connections to open doors for Theranos and assemble a star-studded board of directors (among them Henry Kissinger and James "Mad Dog" Mattis). The media couldn't resist Holmes's story of a college dropout upending a staid industry, and a young woman succeeding in the male-dominated startup world. Many observers linked Holmes's larger than life personality with her memorable physical traits such as her deep voice and her hypnotically large eyes (incidentally, one of the sources interviewed in Bad Blood claims Holmes's deep voice is fake and deliberately cultivated). Also interesting is the role of Sunny Balwani, a Theranos executive who was feared by employees and was romantically involved with Holmes, unknown to the board. Any Theranos employees who expressed misgivings about the company's morally questionable actions faced Balwani's wrath. Theranos's celebrity backers made the company appear to be manifestly legitimate, while Holmes and Balwani carried out what was essentially a scam, gobbling up investor funds and corporate contracts while producing nothing but misleading promises and bogus test results.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carreyrou sticks to the facts in his meticulous and no-nonsense telling of the Theranos story, which leaves the reader with more questions than answers. Theranos could not have gotten as far as it did without the support of its famous advocates, its large corporate partners, and fawning media coverage. How is it possible that all of these respectable people were taken in by Holmes and Balwani's chicanery? How could Holmes be clever enough to gain and betray the trust of America's most prominent public figures while at the same time carrying on a charade that was not only a danger to patients but was also clearly unsustainable? Carreyrou doesn't presume to know the answer to these questions. The reader is simply left with a sense of incredulity.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theranos began to unravel after Carreyrou published a long form exposé in the Wall Street Journal. The latter part of Bad Blood deals with Carreyrou's battle with Theranos's desparate attempts to kill the story. This part of the book especially is a page-turner. Seeing the fraud of Theranos unmasked in the end is a triumph for justice in this quintessentially American saga. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry></feed>